This video introduces project managers
to projects in Microsoft Dynamics 365
Business Central. From the project
manager RO center, we'll use the
navigation list to see our list of
projects. The list shows sample
projects, but we'll create a new one. On
the project card, Business Central
assigns the project number and we'll
enter basic information like a
description. We'll also choose a
customer from our list.
We'll assign ourselves as the project
manager. So our role center will display
the
project. Now we'll create tasks.
Typically the project task number is
part of a number sequence that we
define. We'll keep it simple and use
100, 200, and so on. The description
lets us add information about the task.
We can have a couple of tasks such as
consulting or design services or a list
of many tasks. We'll leave the project
task type set to posting so we can add
budget information on a planning line.
To add budget information, we'll open
the project planning lines window. We
enter the project task number or use the
lookup. The line type can be budget or
billable or both depending on the line
cost and how we bill a customer. We can
also set the planning date and document
number. Next, we'll add items and our
resources, which are the people who will
do the work and the quantity. The cost
and price amounts come from the resource
or item assigned. We can add as many
lines as we
need. Back on the project card task,
show the totals for costs and invoicing
in the project details pane, which helps
us stay on
budget. The posting fast tab is
important as well. We should choose a
project posting group. We can choose
these per project or in the project
setup window. The my projects list on
the project manager role center now
shows our project. When we set up other
similar projects, we can save time by
copying tasks. Let's do that. We choose
new project to start the create new
project assisted setup guide. Business
central assigns a project number. So, we
just need to enter a description and
customer number.
We select the project to copy from and
then specify tasks. We can also leave
them blank to copy all
tasks. If we want, we can copy
quantities and dimensions on the apply
fast tab and then click okay to
finalize. The tasks are now successfully
copied to our brand new project. We can
see the tasks we copied from our
previous project are there. We can then
specify other information based on our
new project.
Thanks for watching.